PRODUCT REQUIREMENTS DOCUMENT ù v1.1 AMENDMENTcwlgen: Blind Spot AnalysisWhat v1.0 missed ù and what we can actually fix nowv1.1 Amendment   ò   June 2026   ò   Harsh ShuklaDocument typev1.0 PRD amendment ù blind spot resolutionAmendscwlgen PRD v1.0 (June 2026)AuthorHarsh Shukla (24BCE7196, VIT-AP University)StatusDraft1. OverviewThis document is an amendment to the cwlgen PRD v1.0. It documents four critical blind spots identified during design review, provides an honest feasibility assessment for each, specifies the solutions that will be implemented in v1.0, and clearly states which limitations remain and are deferred to v2.0.Design philosophyThis amendment follows a single rule: we do not paper over limitations with vague future-work notes. Each problem is either solved completely, solved partially with the residual limitation documented, or honestly deferred with a reason.2. Blind Spot SummaryIDProblemv1.0 ResolutionResidual limitationBS-01Regex breaks on minified JS variable namesPARTIAL: skip var-name patterns on minified files; keep path/key patternsVariable names in minified bundles unrecoverable without AST parserBS-02Sequential JS fetching fails AC-08 under loadFULL: replace with aiohttp async fetchingNone ù fully resolvedBS-03Large JS bundles cause memory/CPU hangPARTIAL: chunked streaming + configurable file size capChunk boundary edge case for matches spanning chunksBS-04SPAs render routes in JS, invisible to BeautifulSoupPARTIAL: source map detection added; static bundle regex improvedRoutes rendered only at runtime require headless browser (v2.0)3. Detailed Analysis and SolutionsBS-01  Regex Brittleness on Minified JavaScriptPARTIALLY SOLVABLE IN V1.0ProblemModern build tools (Webpack, Vite, esbuild) minify JavaScript by renaming variables to single letters. The PRD v1.0 pattern r'(?:var|let|const)\s+\w*[Uu][Rr][Ll]\w*\s*=...' relies on the variable being named something recognizable like apiBaseUrl. After minification this becomes c=..., and the pattern produces zero matches. This affects the entire variable-name extraction family of regex patterns.Solution implemented in v1.0Split JS patterns into two tiers. Tier 1 (minification-safe): path string literals r'["\'](\/[\w\/\-_.?=&%]{2,})["\']' and JSON key patterns r'["\']([a-zA-Z_][a-zA-Z0-9_]{2,30})["\']:\s'. String literals are never renamed by minifiers. Tier 2 (readable-source only): var/let/const name patterns. Add a minification detector: if line_count / char_count < 0.005 (fewer than 5 newlines per 1000 chars), flag the file as minified and skip Tier 2. Run both tiers on non-minified files.Remaining limitationA proper fix requires parsing the JS AST using a tool like esprima or acorn (Node.js). This would recover semantic information even from minified code. This is architecturally complex (requires a Node.js subprocess from a Python tool) and is deferred to v2.0. The v1.0 fix recovers the high-value data (path strings, API keys) while honestly skipping what cannot be recovered.jsscanner.py ù minification detection and tiered patternsMINIFIED_THRESHOLD = 0.005  # newlines per chardef is_minified(js_text: str) -> bool:    if not js_text:        return False    ratio = js_text.count("\n") / len(js_text)    return ratio < MINIFIED_THRESHOLD# Tier 1: minification-safe (always run)T1_PATTERNS = [    re.compile(r'["\'](\/[\w\/\-_.?=&%]{2,})["\'')]'),   # path literals    re.compile(r'["\']([a-zA-Z_][a-zA-Z0-9_]{2,30})["\'"]:\s'),  # JSON keys]# Tier 2: readable source onlyT2_PATTERNS = [    re.compile(r'(?:var|let|const)\s+(\w*[Uu][Rr][Ll]\w*)'),    re.compile(r'(?:var|let|const)\s+([a-zA-Z_$][\w$]{2,30})'),]def scan_js(js_text: str) -> set:    words = set()    minified = is_minified(js_text)    patterns = T1_PATTERNS if minified else T1_PATTERNS + T2_PATTERNS    for pat in patterns:        words.update(pat.findall(js_text))    if minified:        # emit a warning so the user knows they lost Tier 2        print("[!] Minified JS detected ù variable name extraction skipped",              file=sys.stderr)    return wordsBS-02  Sequential JS Fetching ù Performance BottleneckFULLY SOLVABLE IN V1.0ProblemThe v1.0 architecture fetches external JS files sequentially using requests.get() in a for loop. If a target serves 15 JS bundles (common for React apps), each taking ~1s to fetch, the fetching phase alone takes 15s, violating AC-08. There is no benefit to sequential fetching here: the JS URLs are all known before any fetch begins, and the results are independent.Solution implemented in v1.0Replace the JS-fetching loop with aiohttp + asyncio.gather(). All JS file URLs discovered during HTML parsing are passed to an async fetcher that issues all requests in parallel. The HTML fetch itself remains synchronous (it must complete before JS URLs are known). Install: pip install aiohttp. The fetcher module exposes both a sync fetch() for the initial HTML request and an async fetch_all() for the JS bundle phase.Remaining limitationNone. This is a complete fix. The only edge case is targets that enforce strict per-IP concurrency limits, which could cause 429 responses if all 15 bundles are requested simultaneously. Mitigate with a configurable --js-concurrency flag (default: 10) that limits the async semaphore.fetcher.py ù async JS bundle fetchingimport asyncio, aiohttpHEADERS = {"User-Agent": "Mozilla/5.0 Chrome/120"}# Sync: used for initial HTML page fetchdef fetch_html(url, cookies=None, extra_headers=None, timeout=10):    import requests    s = requests.Session()    s.headers.update(HEADERS)    if extra_headers:        s.headers.update(extra_headers)    if cookies:        s.headers["Cookie"] = cookies    r = s.get(url, timeout=timeout)    r.raise_for_status()    return r.text# Async: used for parallel JS bundle fetchingasync def _fetch_one(session, url):    try:        async with session.get(url, timeout=aiohttp.ClientTimeout(total=10)) as r:            return await r.text()    except Exception as e:        print(f"[!] JS fetch failed: {url} ù {e}", file=__import__("sys").stderr)        return ""async def _fetch_all_async(urls, concurrency=10):    sem = asyncio.Semaphore(concurrency)    async def bounded(url):        async with sem:            return await _fetch_one(session, url)    async with aiohttp.ClientSession(headers=HEADERS) as session:        return await asyncio.gather(*[bounded(u) for u in urls])def fetch_all_js(urls, concurrency=10):    """Blocking wrapper ù call from sync code."""    return asyncio.run(_fetch_all_async(urls, concurrency))BS-03  Memory and CPU Exhaustion on Large JS BundlesPARTIALLY SOLVABLE IN V1.0ProblemProduction React/Vue bundles are commonly 2û5MB per file. Loading five of these into memory simultaneously (as v1.0 does with r.text()) and running multiple compiled regex patterns against each is a realistic path to the process hanging at high CPU or being OOM-killed. The problem is compounded when async fetching (BS-02 fix) loads all bundles concurrently.Solution implemented in v1.0Two complementary mitigations. First, a configurable file size cap: after fetching, check len(js_text) against --max-js-size (default: 2MB). If the file exceeds the limit, emit a warning and skip it. This is a blunt instrument but prevents the worst cases. Second, chunked streaming for large files that pass the size check: split the file into 512KB chunks with a 200-byte overlap buffer (so regex matches straddling a chunk boundary are not missed), run patterns per chunk, union results. The overlap is set to max expected match length.Remaining limitationThe chunk overlap approach has one genuine edge case: a match longer than 200 bytes would be split across chunks and missed. In practice, no path string or key name in a JS file is 200+ bytes, so this is acceptable. The real fix is streaming the HTTP response body and running regex on each received chunk before buffering the full response in memory ù this requires aiohttp's content.iter_chunked() and is more complex to implement correctly. Deferred to v2.0.jsscanner.py ù chunked processing with size capMAX_JS_BYTES  = 2 * 1024 * 1024   # 2MB default (overridable via CLI)CHUNK_SIZE    = 512 * 1024          # 512KBOVERLAP_BYTES = 200                 # overlap to catch boundary-spanning matchesdef scan_js_chunked(js_text: str, max_bytes: int = MAX_JS_BYTES) -> set:    if len(js_text.encode()) > max_bytes:        print(f"[!] JS file exceeds {max_bytes//1024}KB cap ù skipped",              file=sys.stderr)        return set()    words = set()    minified = is_minified(js_text)    patterns = T1_PATTERNS if minified else T1_PATTERNS + T2_PATTERNS    # Process in chunks with overlap    encoded = js_text.encode("utf-8", errors="replace")    i = 0    while i < len(encoded):        chunk = encoded[i : i + CHUNK_SIZE + OVERLAP_BYTES].decode(            "utf-8", errors="replace"        )        for pat in patterns:            words.update(pat.findall(chunk))        i += CHUNK_SIZE   # advance by chunk (not chunk+overlap)    return wordsBS-04  SPA Blind Spot ù Routes Rendered at RuntimePARTIALLY SOLVABLE IN V1.0ProblemSingle-page applications built with React Router, Vue Router, or Angular Router define their routes entirely in JavaScript. The server returns a near-empty HTML shell with a single <div id='root'></div> and a bundle reference. BeautifulSoup sees no meaningful links, no form actions, and no visible paths. The actual application structure exists only inside the JS bundle, and within the bundle the routes are often defined as string literals in a router configuration object ù which static regex can partially recover.Solution implemented in v1.0Two additions. First, source map detection: before processing a JS file at bundle.js, probe bundle.js.map. If it exists and is accessible, fetch it ù source maps contain the full pre-minification source as a JSON field (sourceContent array). Scan the original source instead of the minified bundle. This recovers both Tier 1 and Tier 2 patterns. Second, React Router pattern targeting: add a specific regex for JSX route definitions r'path=["\']([/][^"\' ]+)["\']' which matches <Route path="/admin/users"> patterns commonly found in bundle strings even after minification.Remaining limitationSource maps are often intentionally excluded from production deployments for security reasons. When they are absent, static analysis of a minified SPA bundle will recover path literals (Tier 1) but miss dynamically constructed routes like '/api/' + version + '/users' or template literal routes. These are only recoverable by executing the JavaScript ù which requires a headless browser. Playwright/Puppeteer integration is the correct v2.0 solution.fetcher.py + jsscanner.py ù source map probing and JSX route pattern# In fetcher.py ù probe for source mapsdef probe_sourcemap(js_url, fetch_fn):    map_url = js_url + ".map"    try:        raw = fetch_fn(map_url)        data = json.loads(raw)        # sourcesContent is a list of original source file strings        sources = data.get("sourcesContent", [])        return "\n".join(s for s in sources if s)    except Exception:        return None   # map not available# In jsscanner.py ù additional SPA-aware pattern (Tier 1, minification-safe)JSX_ROUTE_PAT = re.compile(r'path=["\'](/[^"\'  ]{1,120})["\'"]')# In pipeline ù use source map if availablefor js_url in js_urls:    source = probe_sourcemap(js_url, fetch_html) or fetched_js[js_url]    words |= scan_js_chunked(source)    words |= set(JSX_ROUTE_PAT.findall(source))4. Updated Module StructureThe following changes to the v1.0 file layout reflect the additions in this amendment:Updated cwlgen/ layoutcwlgen/  cli.py          ù adds --max-js-size, --js-concurrency flags  fetcher.py      ù UPDATED: sync fetch_html() + async fetch_all_js()                             + probe_sourcemap()  extractor.py    ù unchanged  jsscanner.py    ù UPDATED: is_minified(), tiered patterns,                             scan_js_chunked(), JSX_ROUTE_PAT  normalizer.py   ù unchanged  reporter.py     ù UPDATED: logs skipped files (size cap, minification)  utils.py        ù unchanged5. Updated DependenciesPackagePurposeAdded inrequestsSync HTML fetchingv1.0aiohttpAsync parallel JS bundle fetching (BS-02)v1.1asyncioAsync runtime (stdlib)v1.1beautifulsoup4HTML DOM traversalv1.0lxmlFast HTML parser backendv1.0jsonSource map parsing (stdlib)v1.1reRegex patternsv1.0urllib.parseURL normalization (stdlib)v1.06. Updated Acceptance CriteriaThe following criteria replace or augment those in v1.0:IDCriterionReplacesTest methodAC-03aTier 1 patterns (path literals, JSON keys) run on all JS files including minifiedAC-03Inject known paths into a minified test fixtureAC-03bTier 2 patterns (var names) skipped on minified files with stderr warningNEWRun against a webpack bundle; verify warning emittedAC-08aTool completes in under 15s for a page with 15 JS files using async fetchingAC-08time cwlgen against a controlled test serverAC-11Files exceeding --max-js-size are skipped with warning, not crashNEWPass a 3MB fixture file; verify skip warning + clean exitAC-12Source map fetched and scanned when .js.map exists alongside .jsNEWServe a .map file from local test server; verify routes recoveredAC-13JSX path= route strings extracted from SPA bundlesNEWInject <Route path="/secret/admin"> string into test bundle7. Honest Limitations Remaining After v1.1These are not deferred because of effort ù they are deferred because they require a fundamentally different approach.The three problems below cannot be solved with Python requests + regex. Acknowledging this honestly is part of good engineering.7.1 Dynamically constructed routesRoutes assembled at runtime from variables or template literals ù e.g. `/api/${version}/users` or `basePath + '/admin'` ù are invisible to static analysis regardless of how sophisticated the regex is. The string `/api/v2/users` never exists as a literal in the source. Only a JavaScript engine executing the code can produce it. Solution: Playwright headless browser in v2.0.7.2 Routes behind authentication flowsEven with session cookie injection (--cookies), cwlgen scrapes a single page. A route that only becomes visible after completing a multi-step auth flow (OAuth redirect, CSRF token exchange) will be missed. cwlgen cannot navigate a dynamic login flow. Solution: recorded browser session replay in v2.0.7.3 WebSocket and GraphQL surfacescwlgen produces an HTTP path wordlist. WebSocket upgrade endpoints and GraphQL schema fields (types, queries, mutations, arguments) are a completely different attack surface not representable as path wordlists. GraphQL introspection querying is a separate v2.0 feature.8. Updated v2.0 RequirementsFeatureSolvesDependencyPlaywright headless browserBS-04 fully, dynamic routes, auth flowsplaywright Python packageJS AST parser (esprima/acorn)BS-01 fully ù variable names in minified codeNode.js subprocessStreaming HTTP response bodyBS-03 fully ù true zero-copy memory usageaiohttp content.iter_chunked()GraphQL introspectionWebSocket/GQL surface coveragegql or httpxRecursive crawlerMulti-page coverageInternal link queue + depth limit9. Change LogVersionDateAuthorChangesv1.0June 2026Harsh ShuklaInitial PRDv1.1June 2026Harsh ShuklaBlind spot analysis; BS-01/02/03/04 assessment; async fetching, chunked scanning, source map probing, tiered JS patterns added
